colliers.com 2006-06-17

# Colliers International: Privacy Policy

Colliers.com is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. It is our belief that you should understand how we use any information that you provide to us and, furthermore, that you should have the right to approve the use of that information.

In the handling of your information, we follow a policy of "informed consent", that is to say:

In using the varied features of this web site, you may occasionally provide information, such as your name, your contact information, or other information about yourself by which others may identify you (hereinafter "Personal Information"), to Colliers.com, our service providers, or to other businesses which you may contact while visiting our site. Colliers.com and these other entities may use this information and other technical information about your use of this web site to tailor their presentations to you, to facilitate your movement through this web site, or communicate separately with you, however, Colliers.com will never intentionally provide any of your Personal Information to other companies or individuals without your express permission to do so, we will notify you at the time of such data collection or transfer if your Personal Information is to be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting such sharing.

The following document will let you know how we are using the information that you provide to us.

**1\. What Personal Information does Colliers.com collect from you?**

  Colliers.com collects information in several ways from different parts of our web site.

Some Personal Information is gathered when you sign up for our newsletter, enter a site feedback form, or complete a client satisfaction survey. During the on-line registration process, for example, Colliers.com may ask for your name, email address, telephone number, postal code, occupation, industry information and professional interests. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to assist you with your real estate needs.

  **2\. What are cookies and how does Colliers.com use them?**

As part of offering customized and personalized on-line services, Colliers.com uses cookies to store information. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow Colliers.com to provide you with a more personalized experience when you visit our sites, to customize the information that you receive as part of the monthly newsletter and to be able to contact you when we have properties or information that you have requested.

Cookies from Colliers.com can only be read by Colliers.com. And, if you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you will still be able to access most of the areas on this site. However, please note that if you disable all cookies using your browser, you may not be able to edit your newsletter profile. So, if you wish to edit your newsletter profile, make sure that you have not configured your browser so as to disable all cookies.

**3\. How does Colliers.com use Personal Information?**

Colliers.com's primary goal in collecting Personal Information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our network of sites. This includes personalized services, interactive communications, online transactions and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide such services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Colliers.com is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. Colliers.com does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this in order to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Colliers.com may share aggregated user data with advertisers or business partners, however, Colliers.com will never intentionally provide any of your Personal Information to other companies or individuals without your permission to do so and will take all reasonable steps to protect such Personal Information from perpetrators of fraud or internet piracy.

**4\. Who is collecting information?**

When you are on a Colliers.com site and are asked for Personal Information, you are sharing that information with Colliers.com alone unless it is specifically stated otherwise.

**5\. With whom does Colliers.com share my information?**

As a general rule, Colliers.com will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information to anyone outside of Colliers International without your permission to do so.

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Colliers.com will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them.

HOWEVER, PLEASE NOTE THAT AS PART OF ITS PRIVACY POLICY COLLIERS.COM RESERVES THE RIGHT TO TAKE ANY ACTION WITH RESPECT TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WHICH WE, IN OUR SOLE AND ABSOLUTE DISCRETION, DEEM NECESSARY OR APPROPRIATE IF SUCH INFORMATION MAY CREATE A LIABILITY FOR US OR MAY CAUSE US TO LOSE ALL OR PART OF THE SERVICES PROVIDED TO US BY OUR INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDERS OR OTHER SUPPLIERS.

  **6\. What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

Colliers.com may, from time to time, send you e-mail regarding our services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Colliers.com, we may occasionally send you direct mail about services which we feel may be of interest to you. Only Colliers.com (or agents working on behalf of Colliers.com under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. At any time you can easily edit your Colliers.com account information to no longer receive such offers and mailings.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. As mentioned earlier, by modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is about to be set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to edit your newsletter profile. So, as mentioned earlier, if you wish to edit your newsletter profile, make sure that you have not configured your browser so as to reject all cookies.

**7\. How does Colliers.com protect my personal and business-related information?**

Keeping your information private is vitally important to us. As with all information, Colliers.com will never rent or sell your personal and business-related information without your express permission.

**8\. What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your Colliers.com Profile Information are accessed by the cookies on your computer so that only you should have access to this Profile Information. You may edit your Colliers.com Profile Information by logging on to the Colliers.com Website from your computer.

We recommend that you sign out of your Colliers.com account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This will help ensure that others cannot access your Personal Information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or an Internet cafe.

As a global company Colliers.com has international sites and users all over the world. When you give Colliers.com Personal Information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country or jurisdiction where you originally entered the information. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever Colliers.com handles Personal Information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, Colliers.com takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Use Agreement and this Privacy Policy.

**9\. What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you disclose Personal Information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post Personal Information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

PLEASE REMEMBER THAT NO DATA TRANSMISSION OVER THE INTERNET CAN BE GUARANTEED TO BE 100% SECURE. AS A RESULT, WHILE WE STRIVE TO PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, COLLIERS.COM CANNOT ENSURE OR WARRANT THE SECURITY OF ANY INFORMATION YOU TRANSMIT TO US AND YOU DO SO AT YOUR OWN RISK. ONCE WE RECEIVE YOUR TRANSMISSION, WE MAKE OUR BEST EFFORT TO ENSURE ITS SECURITY ON OUR SYSTEMS.

**10\. Applicable Law**

This Privacy Policy is intended be governed by, construed and enforced in accordance with the laws of the Province of Ontario. Any action which you or any third party may bring in connection with this policy, shall be brought only in the courts of the Province of Ontario, and you expressly consent to the jurisdiction of the courts of the Province of Ontario.

**11\. Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [contact@colliers.com](mailto:contact@colliers.com).

COLLIERS.COM TERMS OF USE AGREEMENT

Welcome to Colliers.com.

We have set up some ground rules to ensure that we keep this area useful, informative and safe for everyone. Colliers.com is built on trust, and this Agreement helps promote that trust among all Users of our service.

THIS AGREEMENT DESCRIBES THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS UNDER WHICH YOU WILL USE THE SERVICES AT COLLIERMN.COM. BY COMPLETING YOUR ONLINE REGISTRATION FOR COLLIERMN.COM YOU AGREE TO ALL OF THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS SET OUT IN THIS AGREEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY OF THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS SET OUT IN THIS AGREEMENT, PLEASE DO NOT USE THIS SITE.

Colliers.com reserves the right to change these guidelines and disclaimers at anytime, and you agree that each visit you make to the Colliers.com Web Site shall be subject to the current guidelines. If you have any questions that this guide does not answer, please contact [contact@colliers.com](mailto:contact@colliers.com). Except as otherwise provided herein, this Terms of Use Agreement applies to all Users of any service at Colliers.com.

* * *

**1\. Defined Terms**

In this Agreement, the following words or expressions have the following meanings:

"Colliers.com" means Colliers International and shall include any subsidiaries, parent companies affiliates, officers or employees of Colliers International and any Internet services operated by Colliers International, Colliers.com and any related or affiliated companies.

"Personal Information" means information by which others might identify you, such as your name or your contact information, which you may provide to Colliers.com from time to time.  
"User" means any user of the Colliers.com service.

**2\. No Resale of Services or Information**

You agree not to resell information obtained from Colliers.com without the express permission of Colliers.com.

**3\. Disputes**

In the event that you have a dispute with one or more other Users, you release Colliers.com (and our agents and employees) from claims, demands and damages (actual and consequential) of every kind and nature, known and unknown, suspected and unsuspected, disclosed and undisclosed, arising out of or in any way connected with such disputes.

**4\. Limit on Liability**

In no event shall Colliers.com or its suppliers be liable for lost profits or any special, incidental or consequential damages (however arising, under contract, tort or any other theory of liability) arising out of or in connection with this Agreement. Our liability, and the liability of our suppliers, to you or to any third parties in any circumstance is limited to the greater of (a) the amount of fees you pay to us in the 12 Months prior to the action giving rise to liability, or (b) $100.

**5\. System Integrity**

You as a User agree not to use any device, software or routine to interfere or attempt to interfere with the proper operation of the Colliers.com site or any service being provided on our site. You agree not to take any action that imposes an unreasonable or disproportionately large load on our web site infrastructure. If you are issued a password, you agree not to disclose your password to any third party or to use your password for any unauthorized purpose.

**6\. Web Links**

Colliers.com may display URLs or icons which allow Users to link to other web sites, including, without limitation, sites which are operated by third parties and which are not maintained by Colliers.com. Colliers.com makes no representations whatsoever about any other web site to which you may have access through this site. Any content, services, representations or warranties made on such other web sites are the sole responsibility of the operator of those sites, and Colliers.com assumes no responsibility for any the content, the operation or the services provided thereon.

**7\. Privacy Policy**

Our current privacy policies may be viewed by clicking the "Privacy Policy" link at the bottom of this page and shall form part of this Terms of Use Agreement.

PLEASE NOTE THAT, AS PART OF OUR PRIVACY POLICY, COLLIERS.COM DOES RESERVE THE RIGHT TO TAKE ANY ACTION WITH RESPECT TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT WE, IN OUR SOLE AND ABSOLUTE DISCRETION, DEEM NECESSARY OR APPROPRIATE IF SUCH INFORMATION MAY CREATE A LIABILITY FOR US OR MAY CAUSE US TO LOSE ALL OR PART OF THE SERVICES PROVIDED TO US BY OUR INTERNET SERVICE PROVIDERS OR OTHER SUPPLIERS.

**8\. Indemnification**

You as a User agree to indemnify and hold harmless Colliers.com,, from any claim or demand made by any third party arising out of the use of the services provided by Colliers.com by you or by any other person using your User name and password. You also agree to indemnify and hold harmless Colliers.com against all of the reasonable costs of defending any such third party claims.

**9\. No Warranty**

WE PROVIDE THE COLLIERS.COM WEBSITE AND OUR SERVICES "AS IS" AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY OR CONDITION, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED. WE AND OUR SUPPLIERS SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIM THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF TITLE, MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, EXPECTATION OF PRIVACY AND NON-INFRINGEMENT.

WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, COLLIERS.COM MAKES NO WARRANTY THAT (I) THE SERVICES AND MATERIALS WILL MEET YOUR REQUIREMENTS, (II) THE SERVICES WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED, SECURE, OR ERROR-FREE, OR (III) THE CONTENT OBTAINED FROM THE USE OF THE SERVICES WILL BE EFFECTIVE, ACCURATE OR RELIABLE.

**10\. General Compliance with Laws**

You as a User agree to comply with all applicable laws, statutes, ordinances and regulations regarding your use of our service.

**11\. No Agency**

You and Colliers.com are independent contractors, and no agency, partnership, joint venture, employee-employer or franchiser-franchisee relationship is intended, implied or created by this Agreement.

**12\. Notices**

Except as explicitly stated otherwise, any notices shall be transmitted to Colliers.com by e-mail to [contact@colliers.com](mailto:contact@colliers.com) (in the case of notices sent to Colliers.com) or to you the User at the e-mail address which you provide to Colliers.com during the registration process. Notice shall be deemed given 72 hours after e-mail is sent, unless the sending party is notified that the e-mail address is invalid. Alternatively, we may give you notice by certified mail, postage prepaid and return receipt requested, to the address provided to Colliers.com during the transaction or bid process. In such case, notice shall be deemed given 3 days after the date of mailing.

**13\. Trademarks**

"Colliers.com", the Colliers.com logo and the products and services described in this Site, are without limitation either trademarks of Colliers.com or its suppliers and licensors, and may not be copied, imitated or used, in whole or in part, without the prior written permission of Colliers.com. In addition, all page headers, custom graphics, button icons and scripts are service marks, trademarks and/or trade dress of Colliers.com, and may not be copied, imitated or used, in whole or in part, without the prior written permission of Colliers.com. All other trademarks, registered trademarks, and company names or logos mentioned herein are the property of their respective owners.

**14\. Applicable Law**

This Terms of Use Agreement shall be governed by the laws of the Province of Ontario and the parties hereby irrevocably attorn to the jurisdiction of the courts of the Province of Ontario.

**15\. Severability**

If any provision of this Agreement shall be held to be invalid, illegal or unenforceable, the validity, legality or enforceability of the remaining provisions of this Agreement shall not in any way be affected or impaired thereby.

**16\. Currency**

Unless otherwise indicated, all dollar amounts referred to in this and other web-sites provided by Colliers.com are in Canadian funds.

**17\. Entire Agreement and Waiver**

This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between the Colliers.com and the User and supersedes all prior agreements, understandings, negotiations and discussions, whether oral or written, between the parties with respect thereto. No supplement, modification, waiver or termination of this Agreement shall be binding unless executed in writing by the person to be bound thereby. No waiver of any of the provisions of this Agreement shall constitute or be deemed a waiver of any other provisions (whether or not similar) or a continuing waiver unless otherwise expressly provided.

**18\. Your Correspondence**

We encourage you to share your comments and questions with other users and us. We promise to read all the mail you send to us, but we may not be able to respond to all of them. Please note that we assume no responsibility for reviewing unsolicited ideas for our business (such as product or advertising ideas) and will not incur any liability as a result of any similarities that may appear in future programs. Also, please remember that you are responsible for whatever material you submit, and that you, and not Colliers.com, have full responsibility for the message, trade secrets or other confidential information in your messages. Any and all rights to materials and ideas submitted to us become the exclusive property of Colliers.com.

**19\. Additional Information**

Questions regarding this Terms of Use Agreement should be directed to [contact@colliers.com.](mailto:contact@colliers.com.)

Copyright © 2003 Colliers International. All rights reserved.
